In this video, we will test the algorithm
在本视频中，我们将测试
for a pattern of blue and red squares on a grid.
网格上蓝色和红色方块图案的算法。
Remember that testing is going to make us more confident in our algorithm,
请记住，测试将使我们对算法更有信心，
since generalizing is one of the harder parts of the programming process and is
因为泛化是编程过程中最困难的部分之一，并且
prone to errors such as leaving something constant that should be a variable.
很容易出现错误，例如将本应是变量的东西保持不变。
We need a grid to draw on,
我们需要一个可以绘制的网格，
an arrow to keep track of where in the algorithm we are,
一个用来跟踪我们在算法中的位置的箭头，
and a box to list our variables in.
以及一个用来列出变量的方框。
Let's use two for our value of N. We make a box for x and start counting at zero.
让我们用 2 来表示 N 的值。我们为 x 做一个方框然后从零开始计数。
Then we make a box for y and start counting at x's value which is zero here.
然后我们为 y 做一个方框，然后从 x 的值开始计数，这里为零。
Now, we need to decide if x plus y is a multiple of three.
现在，我们需要确定 x 加 y 是否是三的倍数。
It is, so we go inside the if statement and put a blue square at zero, zero.
确实如此，所以我们进入 if 语句并在零、零处放一个蓝色方块。
Now, there are no more steps for this iteration of y,
现在，y 的迭代没有更多的步骤，
so we continue counting with y equals one.
所以我们继续计数 y 等于 1。
Zero plus one is not a multiple of three,
零加一不是三的倍数，
so we enter the otherwise clause and put a red square at zero, one.
所以我们输入其他子句并在零、一处放一个红方块。
There are no more steps for this y,
这个 y 没有其他步骤，
so we'll count the next one.
所以我们将计算下一个步骤。
Zero plus two is not a multiple of three,
零加二不是三的倍数，
so we'll put a red square at zero, two.
所以我们要在零、二处放一个红方块。
We continue counting, and y is three.
我们继续计数，y 等于三。
But we were only counting from x to N so we don't do any of these steps.
但是我们只是从 x 到 N 进行计数，所以我们没有执行任何这些步骤。
And we continue counting for x,
我们继续对 x 进行计数，
so now, x is one.
所以现在，x 是 1。
We're going to count from one to N and call that y.
我们要从 1 到 N 数然后称之为 y。
One plus one is not a multiple of three,
一加一不是三的倍数，
so we put a red square at one, one.
所以我们在一、一处放一个红方块。
Incrementing y, one plus two is a multiple of three,
递增 y，一加二是三的倍数，
so we put a blue square at one, two.
所以我们在一、二处放一个蓝色方块。
We're done counting for y,
我们已经完成了 y 的计
so next, we count our next x.
数，所以接下来，我们计算下一个的 x。
Counting from two to two,
从二到二计数，
two plus two is not a multiple of three,
二加二不是三的倍数，
so we put a red square.
所以我们放一个红方块。
We finished counting for y,
我们完成了 y 的计数，
so we count for the next x.
所以我们对下一个 x 进行计数。
We're done counting for x since we only want to count to N which is two.
我们已经完成了 x 的计数，因为我们只想计数到 N，也就是二。
So we're done with the counting,
所以我们完成了计数，
and we finished executing this algorithm.
我们完成了这个算法的执行。
We are done, and we found the answer we expect.
我们已经完成了，我们找到了我们所期望的答案。
We can say our algorithm,
我们可以说我们的算法
at least, works for N equals 2.
至少适用于 N 等于 2。
We're a little bit more confident in our algorithm because we've shown it to be
我们对自己的算法更有信心了，因为我们已经证明它
correct for at least one value of N that was not what we used to come up with it.
对于至少一个 N 值是正确的，而这不是我们以前想出的。
If we wanted to be more confident,
如果我们想更加自信，
we would have to test it more thoroughly.
就必须对其进行更彻底的测试。
As always, testing can't prove that it's correct,
与往常一样，测试无法证明它是正确的，
it can only make us more and more confident.
它只会让我们越来越自信。